<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>CityScoots</title>
        <description>Thoughts on the latest electric scooters from an obsessed Boston-based rider</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 23:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>The best city scooter of 2020 - The e-TWOW GT</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The e-TWOW Booster GT scooter vastly exceeded my expectations and as of March 2020, it’s my pick for the best city / commuting / portable scooter out there at any price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put way too many hours into the &lt;a href=&quot;/Xiaomi-m365&quot;&gt;Xiaomi m365 scooter&lt;/a&gt; (aka the Mi). In fact, I’ve owned multiple over the past years and have adored it ever since I tried one retrofitted for Bird scooter rental. As I stated in my rundown of the Xiaomi Mi Scooter, it was my pick for best city commuter scooter… until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selection-criteria&quot;&gt;Selection Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late January 2020 I started doing research on the latest and greatest electric scooters out there and began my quest to find something that might topple the m365 as the king. I searched around and applied some important metrics for “success” in my case. Namely &lt;strong&gt;weight&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;speed/power&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;range&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ride comfort&lt;/strong&gt;, and finally &lt;strong&gt;price&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s my detailed rundown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight&quot;&gt;Weight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After injuring my arm lifting the $1,000 &lt;a href=&quot;/WideWheel&quot;&gt;Mercane WideWheel scooter&lt;/a&gt; (which clocks in at 50 lbs!!!), I vowed to cap my scooter prospects at a maximum weight for sanity/usability. As someone who rides once or twice a day and needs to lift a scooter up a 3-step staircase to get it into my home, I set a new weight cap of “under 30lb”. The m365 scooter is 27.5lb and hasn’t given me too much trouble so I figured 30lb would be a logical top end. The e-TWOW GT weighs in at 26.5lbs, which is honestly a miracle of science as they were able to pack in twice the power of the m365 and the battery allows for over twice the range! The size and weight on the e-TWOW GT is impressive for what it contains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;speed--power&quot;&gt;Speed / Power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing is really fast! Thanks to the speedometer, I know that it regularly hits between 23mph and 25mph and I weigh about 190lbs with my gear on. According to the specs, it has a 700w engine and I haven’t had any issues with it being unable to climb hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;range&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as range goes, it gets about 2.5x to 3x the range in practice that my modified m365 gets. The firmware hack on my m365 that enables it to hit 18mph instead of the stock 15mph definitely hurts its range so keep that in mind with the comparison. Regardless, I’m able to do 5-mile each way journeys (10-mile round trip) and make it back with around ~40% battery to spare while maxing out my speed the whole time, which is impressive! I haven’t had a trip yet that pushed my battery down under 40%. If I do, I’ll update this to reflect how that went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ride-comfort&quot;&gt;Ride Comfort&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally I like to stick to pneumatic tires solely for the comfort factor. I’ve ridden too many solid tire scooters on bumpy roads and felt like my teeth were about to chatter out of my head. Without exaggeration, I’ve felt like my arms were losing sensitivity from all the vibrations on some electric scooters (looking at you Segway Ninebot ES2!). The e-TWOW GT has solid tires which I was definitely fearful of, but the dual suspension shocks have done a surprisingly good job of smoothly easing over bumps. I’d say its about 90% as comfortable as a large pneumatic tire like the 8.5” tube tires on the m365. The value of not worrying about flat tires definitely makes up for the missing 10% in comfort as reliability is important to me as well. I have changed two tires on my m365 and I will NEVER DO IT AGAIN (opting to buy a whole new wheel to avoid the tire replacement process). All in all, the comfort on the e-TWOW GT is quite good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;price&quot;&gt;Price&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of February 2020, the e-TWOW GT is surprisingly hard to find in the US. Right now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ewheels.com/product/new-e-twow-gt-700w-504wh-25mph/&quot;&gt;eWheels.com&lt;/a&gt; has them in stock, which is where I purchased mine for $1089. It was well worth the relatively high price and is a serious upgrade over the m365 but I can see how $399 compared to almost $1100 could give some folks pause. For me, as someone who uses this as their primary method of getting around town, it’s a worthwhile investment for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;downsides&quot;&gt;Downsides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, rough patches on the road can be felt with the solid tires more-so than on the m365 (but the reliability of the solid tire plus the shocks helping immensely counter-balance this downside). Additionally, I wish there was a disk brake instead of a magnetic drum brake. The magnetic brake works well and there’s an optional foot-stomp brake for fast stops, but I’d prefer the ease of a single disk brake over the dual-brake setup of the e-TWOW GT. Lastly the charger is a bit large and has a pretty loud fan in it that runs while actively charging. That’s about it for downsides!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-competitors&quot;&gt;Direct Competitors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2019 / early 2020, the next generation of m365 successors began to launch. This includes the m365 PRO and the Segway Ninebot MAX, two scooters in the ~$700 price range that are actually quite similar to one another thanks to the fact that they shared the same production line. At the time of writing, the m365 Pro is not available in the US while the Segway Ninebot MAX is available on Amazon. When it comes right down to it, these are fantastic scooters that improve on the original m365 but they both suffer a similar fate for city riders: the weight is much higher! In fact, the Ninebot MAX is 42.1lb, which violates my ‘under 30lb’ edict. Sure, some people can get away with heavier scooters but for a city rider, it’s definitely a concern. I’m looking forward to spending some time with a Ninebot MAX to see how it handles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy with my upgrade from the m365 to the e-TWOW GT. Sure, the m365 is still a powerful little scooter especially in its price range, but if you’re looking for the best thing out there for city/commuting, my vote goes to the e-TWOW GT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/eTWOW-GT</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eTWOW-GT</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Xiaomi m365 is the first great electric scooter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi m365 is one of the best electric scooters ever made.  For budget-conscious buyers, I recommend it due to its smooth ride, reasonable weight, decent range, and super low price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The m365, also known as the Mi Electric Scooter is one of the most popular scooters on the market. In fact, it was chosen by Bird as the starting scooter model for their rental fleet, likely due to their reliability and quality. The popularity of the m365 no doubt kickstarted the scooter industry into gear, spawning all kinds of competitors trying to live up to the Xiaomi model. I’ve owned two over the past years and have adored it ever since I tried one retrofitted for Bird scooter rental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2 years of ownership, I wanted to write out some of the tips I’ve learned as a m365 owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tires--ride-comfort&quot;&gt;Tires / Ride comfort&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large pneumatic tires on the m365 are second to none. Nothing beats the smooth ride of the m365 air-filled tires. It’s absolutely amazing. &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, the drawbacks are numerous:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat tires happen.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had 3 or 4 of them in the course of 2 years and they are an incredible pain in the butt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replacing flats is very frustrating.&lt;/strong&gt; The process of shimmying the rubber tire on and off and not puncturing the tube in the process is extremely frustrating. I’ve even brought my wheel into bike stores in the Boston area only to have them send me away or in one case a bike tech spent 15 minutes on the floor prying the rubber tire onto the metal wheel only to give up and tell me “its impossible”. Ha! With enough shims and effort, it is doable folks but I found its easier to buy the entire wheel on Amazon, disk brake and all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-buy-off-brand&quot;&gt;Don’t buy off-brand!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a moment of weakness when moving houses, I decided to buy two Mi scooters that I believed were “white label” but in fact were knockoffs. There are a ton of knockoff m365 models out there with less-than-genuine hardware, subpar batteries, and different firmware that doesn’t allow for modification using the “Botox” custom firmware creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-disk-brake-is-fantastic&quot;&gt;The disk brake is fantastic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a disk brake is a big win for the m365. Magnetic brakes are fine but the stopping power of a disk brake is second to none, especially in the rain. Once you’ve used a disk brake, it’s hard to go back to anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weight&quot;&gt;Weight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weight of the m365 is right in the sweet spot, coming in around 27 lbs. I’ve found that any scooter over 30 lbs is just too unwieldy. See my review of the &lt;a href=&quot;/WideWheel&quot;&gt;Mercane WideWheel scooter&lt;/a&gt; for thoughts on heavy scooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speed--power&quot;&gt;Speed / Power&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speed of the m365 is definitely one of the downsides. Capped at 15mph is a bit disappointing once you get used to the scooter. Thankfully, the scooter supports custom firmwares that allow you to increase the speed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;custom-firmware&quot;&gt;Custom firmware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great features of the m365 is that it’s so popular, people have reverse engineered the firmware and allowed for a quick and easy way to increase the speed limit on the device. Using the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://m365.botox.bz/&quot;&gt;https://m365.botox.bz/&lt;/a&gt;, you can choose to adjust engine properties and subsequently load the new firmware onto the scooter with an Android APK linked on that page. It’s not too difficult and can vastly improve the quality of the ride. On mine, I removed the minimum speed needed to start the engine (which normally requires you to be rolling at 1-2mph in order for the engine to kick in), which is a trade-off of battery in exchange for quick acceleration from a stop. Feel free to adjust the properties as needed for your own personal taste!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;range&quot;&gt;Range&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as range goes, the m365 is not &lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;/strong&gt; per se but it’s pretty short. Also when the battery is under 50%, the speed and power suffers drastically. In practice, I’m hesitant to go to destinations over 2.5 miles from my home, as a 5-mile ride brings my battery percentage below 40% and then you get into danger territory. In theory the upgrade to the m365, the m365 MAX is supposed to address this issue but the MAX is so far above my weight maximum that I hesitate to mention it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;price&quot;&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the best feature of the m365 is its incredibly low price. Right now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Xiaomi-Electric-Long-range-Fold-n-Carry-Ultra-Lightweight/dp/B076KKX4BC&quot;&gt;on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, the m365 can be purchased for $377 but I’ve seen it as low as $299. I purchased one in 2018 for $479 and one for my partner in 2019 for $399. No regrets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a starter scooter, the m365 still can’t be beat but if you’re looking for the best thing out there for city/commuting, definitely check out my review of the &lt;a href=&quot;/eTWOW-GT&quot;&gt;e-TWOW GT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/Xiaomi-m365</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Xiaomi-m365</guid>
                
                <category>review</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Mercane WideWheel - Absurdly fast but WEIGHT there's more!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I purchased the 2019 Mercane WideWheel (dual motor) from Fluidfreeride.com for $999 because it was the fastest scooter I could buy and I thought that would be a great idea! Man, was I wrong…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weight&quot;&gt;Weight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After riding the WideWheel for a week, I vowed never to buy a 50lb scooter again. It turns out once you get into that weight category, it’s essentially impossible to carry this thing around or even maneuver it in small spaces. Living in the city and needing to lift the scooter up a curb every once in a while or up even a 2-3 stair set was such an absolute chore. This scooter inspired me to set a limit on the weight for scooters that would fit my needs riding in the city. I describe my new weight limit in my &lt;a href=&quot;/eTWOW-GT&quot;&gt;e-TWOW-GT review.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speed&quot;&gt;Speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this thing screamed. It was incredibly fast. It has immense power for hills and the brakes are fantastic, which is essential for a scooter that can go this fast. Unfortunately the solid airless tires (even with the built in suspension) made it so I felt every bump in the road. I think the travel distance on these shocks is quite low, so that might play a part. Also, when I was riding over 25mph, I felt a little unstable. For context, I have a motorcycle license and have experience riding motorcycles on highways well over 60mph so it was surprising to feel timid hitting 30mph on this. I’m not sure what caused my feelings of instability but I’d bet that a pneumatic tire would help a ton with that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;locking&quot;&gt;Locking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WideWheel comes with a key that you have to have in the ignition to start the scooter, much like a Vespa or moped. In theory this sounds great but Vespas are around 300 pounds and this is 50. It’s heavy but not too heavy for someone to easily steal. I felt a bit scared locking the WideWheel and just leaving it outside destinations. It felt like the key lock mechanism was a bit of a show and didn’t really help give me peace of mind so I needed to bring a U-lock with me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concessions&quot;&gt;Concessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will concede that this scooter might be the optimal scooter for someone out there. Maybe you live in an area where you are able to ride your scooter right into a garage and never have to fold it, move it, or lift it, and you can ride on smooth roads, keeping up with traffic at high speeds. In this case, maybe the WideWheel is the scooter for you! I know, however, that based on my usage patters in a city, commuting and riding around, this was too chunky, heavy, and unwieldy to provide a great experience. But as they say, to each their own!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/WideWheel</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/WideWheel</guid>
                
                <category>tips</category>
                
                <category>work</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>